時は戦国、乱世の時代。
からくり人の住むジパング国では群雄割拠して合戦に明け暮れ、
からくり武芸者たちも勝利と栄光を目指してしのぎを削っていた。
そしていま、からくり武芸者ナンバー１を目指す、とてつもないヒーローが誕生した！
ムサシ、見参でござるだス！
からくり剣豪伝ムサシロード
男はいつでも　世界の真ん中で
いちばん　強くなる日を
AH! AH! 夢見て
心の刃　大空にふりかざし
冒険の旅の　幕を開ける
ジパング国を　さすらう剣豪
その名　からくりびと　ムサシ
GO! FIGHT!
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　昨日よりも　今日　強い
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
明日は　輝くぞ
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　思い切りと　静けさと
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
みけんが　きらめいた　ムサシ！！
반역자라는 오명을 썼던 무사시는 한조의 손에 처형되게 되었다.
Once called a traitor, Musashi was on the verge of the execution by Hanzō.
그러나 그 때, 주베가 검호들을 이끌고 구하러 와 주었다.
But at the right moment, Jūbē and others came to save him.
무사시는 뜨거운 우정에 울고 말았다.
Musashi cried, by the burning hot friendship.
그러나 지팡구 제일의 길은 멀다.
But he still have a long way to go to become the number one of Jipangu.
사내 무사시의 숙명의 길은 어느 방향인가?
Which way is Musashi's road of fate?
무사시, 꿈의 백번승부
Hundred Matches
in Musashi's Dream
설날 기분에서 벗어나지 못한 에도토피아의 거리에 눈이 내리고 있었다.
It was snowing in Edotopia which is still in new year holiday spirit.
그 쯤 무사시는 내일부터의 여행을 앞두고 에도 성에서 센히메, 코지로하고 카드놀이를 하고 있었다.
Meanwhile, Musashi was playing cards with Senhime and Kojirō in Edo castle before leaving for a trip.
이럇!
Mine!
더 이상 재미없소! 난 그만두오!
It's not fun anymore-dasu! I quit-dasu!
오, 난 이렇게나 얻었구나.
Look. I got all of these.
무사시. 그런 반사 신경으로는 제일의 무예가가 될 수 없지.
Musashi. You cannot become the best of Martial Artist with that reflection.
이런 얘들 장난은 코지로한테 딱 어울리오!
Such child's play suits Kojirō perfectly!
뭐라?!
What?!
자, 자, 무사시! 설날이니까 그렇게 화내지 마.
Calm down, Musashi! Don't get mad from the first day of the year!
정말, 왜 너희 둘은 그렇게 사이가 나쁜 거야?
Really, why do you two have a bad relationship?
코지로 따위, 처음 만났을 때부터 정말 싫었소!
I hated Kojirō ever since I saw him for the first time-dasu!
오츠루하고 갈라져 수행길을 떠난 그 날.
The day that I bid farewell to Otsuru and departed for a trip to train myself...
잠, 잠깐 기다리시오!
Wait for a moment-dasu!
기다리라는 건 나 말인가.
Are you talking to me?
상대가 되어 주길 부탁드리오.
I'd like you to be my opponent-dasu.
얼굴에 밥풀이나 붙이고 다니는 주제에 무슨 소리를.
You have rice stuck in your face.
얘야, 식사 후에는 낮잠 자는 게 좋다.
Kiddo, you'd better take a nap after lunch.
꼬마 따위 아니오!
I'm not a kiddo-dasu!
나쁜 소리는 하지 않겠다. 마을에 돌아가서 밭일이나 도와줘라.
I won't say bad things, so you should get back to the village and help people's work.
네이놈, 업신여기지 마시오!
Damn you, don't look down on me!
피해 올라가다니 비겁하오!
It's cowardly to evade an attack-dasu!
뒤에서 달려드는 것은 비겁한 것이 아니냐!
And how about attacking from back?
잡소리 말고 바로 승부를 내오! 자, 오시오!
Don't say useless things and let's have a match-dasu! Come-dasu!
좋다! 무예의 길이란 얼마나 혹독한 것인지 알려 주겠다!
Sure! I'll show the harshness of the road of martial arts!
무사시 등장!
Enter Musashi!
비검! 츠바메가에시!
Secret sword! Tsubamegaeshi!
안녕이다, 무사시. 바보 녀석.
That's farewell for you, Musashi. Idiot.
야! 승부는 아직...
Hey! The match isn't...
말도 안 돼...
No way...
생각하면 또 속이 뒤집어지오!
Thinking about it makes me furious-dasu!
그래도 무사시, 그 때에 비해서 꽤나 강해지지 않았니?
But Musashi, don't you think you did become stronger compared to you of before?
당연하오!
That's obvious-dasu!
나, 보쿠덴 스승님에게 목숨을 걸고 수련받았소!
I was trained under my master Bokuden, risking my life-dasu!
꽤나 쓰라렸지만...
It was pretty bitter-dasu...
무디다! 무뎌!
Soft and naive!
스승님!
Master!
뭔 짓이오!
What are you doing-dasu?!
바보 녀석! 실제 싸움에서 구해주는 놈이 있을 거라 생각하나!
You idiot! Do you think your opponent is going to save you in the real battle?
괜찮은 녀석이었다... 죽을 때까지 검을 놓지 않다니.
He was a fine guy... I'm surprised that he's still holding his sword after death.
츠키아리!
Tsuki Ari!
보쿠덴 스승님, 요즘 어떻게 지내시려나...
I wonder how is Master Bokuden living nowadays.
무사시?
Musashi?
예, 무엇이오?
Yes, what is it-dasu?
아까 오츠루하고 갈라져 수행길을 떠났다고 했잖아?
You told me that you went to train yourself after bidding farewell to Otsuru, right?
오츠루는 누구야?
Who is Otsuru?
설마 무사시의 애인인가?
Could she be Musashi's lover?
어라, 무사시도 가볍게는 못 보겠는걸?
Hey, Musashi isn't to be underestimated, I guess!
졌소!
I lost-dasu!
그 날, 타쿠안 스님에게 혼나서
That day, I was scolded by the monk Takuan,
나무에 매달려진 날 오츠루가 구해주었소!
but Otsuru saved me, hanging down from a tree-dasu!
이제 괜찮네요!
It's all right now!
그래도 오츠루 씨 혼나겠소!
But Otsuru, you're going to be scolded-dasu!
아니에요, 걱정하지 말고 전 무사시 씨가 참새하고 같이 있는 걸 보고 정말 기뻤어요!
Nope. Don't worry. I was happy to see you being with those sparrows!
그러니까 무사시 씨 사실은 정말 마음이 착한 걸 알겠어요!
From that, I understand that you have a kind spirit inside of you!
수줍소...
You make me shy-dasu...
무사시 씨?
Musashi?
뭐오?
What is it?
이거 주먹밥이에요.
I made some rice balls for you.
오츠루 씨!
Otsuru!
스님도 알아주실 거에요.
Master will understand us at last.
그러오.
Hope so.
무사시가 도망쳤다!
Musashi ran away!
-자, 무사시 씨, 빨리!
-알겠소.
-Hurry up, Mr. Musashi!
-Right!
꼭 꿈을 이루세요!
Achieve your dreams!
고맙소. 전 꼭 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 되겠소!
Thank you. I will definitely become the number one Martial Artist of Jipangu-dasu!
오츠루 씨, 저... 저...
Otsuru, I... I...
네, 뭐에요?
Yes, what is it?
저... 작별인사를 해 주면 고맙겠소!
I... I'd like a farewell from you-dasu!
건강하세요, 무사시 씨!
Stay in shape, Musashi!
나, 그 날 정했소. 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 된다면 오츠루를 부인으로 맞이하겠다고!
I decided that day-dasu. I'll have Otsuru as my wife when I become the number one martial artist of Jipangu!
오츠루...
Otsuru...
그래서 무사시.
So, Musashi...
오츠루 씨, 네가 지팡구 제일이 될 때까지 쭉 독신이 되는 거야?
Will Ms. Otsuru have to be a single woman until you become the best in Jipangu?
그, 그렇게 되는 것이겠소.
I... I guess so-dasu.
오츠루도 불쌍하네. 그렇게는 할머니가 되어버리겠어.
Too bad for Otsuru. She'll become a grandmother!
그건 곤란하오!
That won't happen-dasu!
그렇소. 나, 이런 곳에서 놀고 있을 틈 따위 없소!
I got it-dasu. I do not have time to be playing like this-dasu!
시끄러운 놈.
What a noisy brat.
그래도 오츠루는 행복하겠네.
But still, Otsuru will be happy.
그래요.
Right.
아까까지 오던 눈은 평년보다 따뜻한 날씨에 이야기하던 중 그치고 말았다.
The snow has stopped because of weather warmer than previous winters during their conversation.
미야모토 마을의 무사시이오!
I'm Musashi from Miyamoto village-dasu!
주베 님을 뵙고 싶소!
I want to meet Mr. Jūbē-dasu!
환영합니다, 무사시 님.
Welcome, Mr. Musashi.
그래도 이런 시간에 어쩐 일이십니까?
It must be something important to find me this late.
나, 주베 씨를 이기고 싶소. 상대해 주시기를 부탁드리오!
I want to defeat Mr. Jūbē-dasu. I ask you to be my opponent-dasu!
이것 역시 무사시 님답군요.
This also is expected from Mr. Musashi.
일단 앉아서 이야기를 해 보죠.
Let's have a talk first. Please sit down.
무사시 님. 무예가라는 것은 무예만을 닦는 자일까요?
Mr. Musashi. Does a Martial Artist improves martial art skills?
그러니까, 무예가라고 하니까, 역시 무예를 닦는 것이 제일이오.
That is, since it is called a Martial Artist-dasu, polishing Martial Arts skills is the top priority-dasu.
싸움이라는 것에는 전술, 전략이라는 것이 필요.
Tactics and strategy are required in a battle.
곧, 병법서를 공부하는 것이 제일의 무예가의 길.
In short, studying the book of strategy is the road of becoming a first-class Martial Artist.
나, 책을 잘 읽지 못하오.
I am bad at reading books-dasu.
만화는 좋소만.
I like comics, thought-dasu.
뭐든 책을 읽는 것만이 공부인 것은 아닙니다.
Reading isn't everything in studying.
그 외에, 공부할 방법이 있소?
Is there any other way to study-dasu?
나, 가능한 한 간단한 게 좋소.
I'd like the simplest one-dasu.
쫌만 하면 팍 되는 놈으로.
The magical one that works with the least effort!
그런 건 없습니다.
That isn't possible.
역시이오...
Not surprising...
일단은 라이벌에게서 배우는 것입니다.
First of all, you can learn from your rival.
라이벌이오?
From a rival-dasu?
무사시 님이 지금까지 만난 무예가를 생각해 보신다면 알 수 있습니다.
If you think about the Martial Artists that you met until now, you will understand.
내가 만난 무예가...
The Martial Artists I met...
수행길을 떠난 나는 미야코 궁전에서 벤케이를 만났소.
After leaving for training, I met Benkei in Miyako Palace.
나오셨소, 벤케이! 무사시가 상대해 주겠소!
You came out, Benkei! Musashi will face you-dasu!
알겠소? 전력으로 승부를 보겠소!
Got it? Let's have a match to death-dasu!
관둬라, 관둬! 오늘밤은 기념할 만한 천번째의 밤.
Give it up and shoo! Today is the monumental thousandth night.
그 상대는 실력있는 거물로 정했다.
I decided the opponent to be a important person.
자! 얘야! 얼렁 비켜라!
Now, get lost, kid!
닥치시오! 난 아이가 아니오! 검성 보쿠덴의 가르침을 받은 제일의 제자이오!
Shut up! I am not a kid! I am the only student of Bokuden, the master Martial Artist!
시끄러운 애새끼가!
What a noisy kid!
산 지 얼마 안 된 칼이...
I bought this sword today and...
벌써 여기까지군. 게임 오버다.
I see it's settled. Game over.
이렇게 됐으면 삶든지 태우던지 맘대로 하시오!
I don't care anymore even if you boil or set me on fire literally!
방해하지 마라! 얼렁 비켜라!
Don't interfere! Just get lost!
그 때, 그 우시와카가 나타났소.
That moment, that Ushiwaka appeared.
멈춰라.
Stop.
뭔가?
What is it?
그 허리에 있는 것을 가져가겠다.
I will take what you have on your waist.
오? 이걸?
You mean this?
그쪽의 금 야태도, 참으로 나의 천 번째로 어울리는 것.
Your gold large war sword will be a perfect fit for the thousandth item of my collection.
순순히 주지 않겠는가?
Wouldn't you obediently pass it over?
싫다.
No way.
그렇다면... 얻어서 내 것으로 만들 때까지!
If then... we'll fight until I get that!
이놈!
You bastard!
미야코를 휩쓰는 고얀놈, 내가 퇴치하겠다!
I'll get rid of the scoundrel that rampages in Miyako!
뭐시라?!
What?!
놀리지 마라!
Don't make me laugh!
뭔 일이냐?
What's the problem?
젠장... 웃기지 마라!
Damn... don't fool around!
뭐야?!
What?!
어떻냐. 내가 어떻게든 원하는 대로 되던가?
How's that? Did you manage to make me pass the sword?
뭔 이까짓 걸로...
That's insignificant.
져, 졌다. 제가 졌습니다.
I lost, as you see.
오늘 밤의 장물, 더욱 수련해야겠구나.
Tonight's useless thing should train more.
기, 기다려 주십시오! 일단 존함을!
Please wait! Tell me your name!
나는 우시와카. 우시와카라 하오.
I am Ushiwaka. You may call me Ushiwaka.
우시와카 님... 아! 기다려 주십시오!
Ushiwaka... Ah! Please wait!
제발! 부디! 벤케이를!
Please! I beg of you! Have Benkei!
나, 그 때, 위에는 위가 있다는 것을 깨달았소.
That moment, I realized that there is something above a thing that is already above me.
하늘은 공평하다고 하지만...
They say that the god does not give two gifts, but...
우시와카 씨는 미남에, 게다가 강하기까지 하니 앙큼하오!
Not only Mr. Ushiwaka is a handsome man, but he's also strong, and that's unfair-dasu!
무사시 님도 꽤 하는 남자랍니다.
Mr. Musashi, you're a pretty good man too.
정말이오?
Really-dasu?!
역시!
As I expected!
수줍어하고 있을 때냐, 무사시! 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
This is no time to be shying, Musashi! Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
무사시와 주베의 무예담은 밤이 깊어져도 끝나지 않았따.
There was no end to Musashi and Jūbē's conversation even in deep night.
그리고 저와 같이 있을 때 만난 자가 호조인 님.
And we met Mr. Houzouin when we were walking together.
그 사람도 강했소!
That person was strong too-dasu!
다음은 호조인 님과 승부를 보고 싶소!
I want to have a match against Houzouin-dasu!
칼을 나에게 향하는 것은 좋은 자신감이다. 좋다.
Some confidence you have, to aim your sword to me. Good then.
다만 진검승부 이외에는 하지 않겠다. 괜찮나?
But I do not have a match without a real sword. Are you all right with this?
바라던 바이오!
That's what I wanted-dasu!
이상한 창이오!
That's a weird spear-dasu!
이 미늘창이야말로 우리 호조인류의 필살무기!
This kamayari is our Houjouin family's special weapon!
자! 승부다!
Match starts!
쇠붙이 부분을 계산에 넣지 않았소.
I didn't put the metal part to my calculations-dasu...
보았나? 이게 호조인류 미늘창의 특기. 그것뿐만이 아니라 자르는 기능도 있는 만능 창.
Did you see? This is the specialty of kamayari of us Houzouin-ryu. This spear also can cut. It is capable of anything.
각오해라!
Prepare yourself!
이건 허점을 이용할 틈이 전혀 없소!
I cannot find a way to take advantage of anything-dasu!
끝장이다!
Finishing move!
달아가냐, 꼬맹아!
Are you running away, you brat?!
아니오! 좁은 도장에서는 의의가 막히니까 밖으로 나왔을 뿐이오!
That's not it! I just came out because my spirit was blocked inside the limited space inside Dōjō!
패배를 인정하기 1초 전이군!
One second before you admit your loss!
움직일 수가 없소!
I cannot move-dasu!
이럇, 찌르기다!
Piercing move!
각오해라!
Prepare yourself!
누구냐!
Who did that?!
네이놈.
How dare you...
너는...
You're...
상대는 아직 소년. 굳이 날뛰어야 한다면 소생이 상대하겠습니다.
The opponent is a boy. If you must be savage, I will content with you.
접시꽃 문장. 제국을 돌아보는 경찰 장관 주베 님인가...
Emblem of hollyhock. He must be Jūbē, the director of police who takes care of whole empire...
승부를 잊었소, 호조인? 각오하시오!
Did you forget the match-dasu, Houzouin? Prepare yourself!
졌소.
I lost.
어째서오? 지금 승부는 비긴 것이...
Why-dasu? This match is a draw...
아니오. 자랑스러운 창이 끊어진 제가 진 것이오.
No. It is my loss because my spear of pride is cut off.
이후, 정진하겠소이다.
I will devote more, from now on.
저, 정말이오?
Re- really?
해냈다! 해냈소!
I did it! I did it-dasu!
그 때의 무사시 님도 강했지요.
Mr. Musashi, you were strong too back then.
그래도 주베 씨 덕이오!
But it's all thanks to Mr. Jūbē-dasu!
그리고 쿠사리가마를 쓰는 바이켄 님.
And Mr. Baiken, the user of Kusarigama.
그런 무기, 나 그 때 처음 봤소!
I never saw a weapon like that before then-dasu!
저런!
No!
뭔 짓이오!
What are you doing-dasu?!
멈춰라!
Stop that!
멈추라는 말이 안 들리나!
Don't you hear me?!
내가 졌다.
I lost.
아니오. 아직 승부가 나지 않았소.
No. The match isn't over yet-dasu.
라이벌을 넘은 우정이란 것이겠소.
Friendship comes before rivalry.
이 소리는?
What is this sound?
내 배가 비었소. 배고파졌소...
My stomach is empty-dasu. I'm now hungry...
알겠습니다. 식사를 준비해 드리지요.
Alright. I'll get you a meal.
맛있소!
It's so good-dasu!
그런데 무사시 님.
By the way, Mr. Musashi...
그 콩을 젓가락 하나로 집을 수 있을까요?
Can you pick one of those beans with one chopstick?
하나로?
One?
젓가락 하나로는 무리이오.
It's impossible with only one chopstick-dasu!
그럼 둘이라면 어떻습니까.
Then how about two?
이거라면 쉽소.
This is easy-dasu.
그런 것입니다.
That's how it is.
그런 것?
That's how it is?
코지로 님에게 츠바메가에시라는 비검이 있다고 해도,
Mr. Kojirō may have a secret sword named Tsubamegaeshi,
그 칼은 하나.
he uses only one sword.
칼은 둘이 있다!
You have two swords!
이도류...
Dual blade...
언젠가 우연히 보여주신 이도류의 기술.
Technique of dual blade that you showed me by chance.
그걸 공부한다면...
If you explore about it...
이도류...
Dual blade...
무예 대회에서의 무사시와 주베의 번외 시합.
Musashi and Jūbē's extra match in the martial arts competition.
시작!
Start!
안 돼! 이대로는 당하오! 이대로는!
No! I'll be done for in this rate-dasu! I need something!
어떻게 타개할 방법은 없소?
Is there a way to get over-dasu?
그 때, 우연히 보여준 것이 이도류였다.
What he showed us back then is the technique of dual blade.
그 자세를 공부한다면 천하무적의 무예가가 될 지도 모릅니다.
If you explore about that posture, you might become the matchless Martial Artist as well.
이도류를 공부하는 것이겠소!
So I should study dual blade-dasu!
코지로 님과 함께 여행하면서 자신의 검술을 수련하며 이도류를 완성하는 건 어떨지요.
I suggest you to make your technique of dual blade excellent during the journey with Kojirō.
알겠소. 나, 꼭 이도류를 공부해서 숙명의 라이벌, 코지로를 쓰러뜨리겠소!
Understood-dasu. I will take Kojirō down by studying the technique of dual blade-dasu!
이도류를 완성한 새벽녘에는 이 괴물을 퇴치하십시오.
When you completed your technique of dual blade, you will eliminate these monsters.
야마타노오로치?
Yamata no Orochi?
츠치구모?
Tsuchigumo?
신이 다스리던 시대부터 명도 천공환, 천지환을 지키고 있다고 전해지는 괴물입니다.
(Tenkūmaru: Sword of the sky, Tenchimaru: Sword of the world)
They are monsters that are told to be protecting the sacred swords named Tenkūmaru and Tenchimaru.
그 괴물을 퇴치하면 그 명도가 손에 들어오는 것이오!
So by getting rid of those monsters, I will be able to have those excellent swords!
그 때야말로 무사시 님은 천하제일의 검호가 되겠죠.
When that time comes, Mr. Musashi, you'll become the best of the master swordsmen in the world.
주베 씨, 감사하오!
Thank you so much, Mr. Jūbē-dasu!
나, 힘껏 해 보겠소!
I'll do that with all my might!
이것이 바로 무사시의 이천일류 개안의 힌트가 되긴 했지만
(Nitenichiryū: 二天一流; other name for Nitouryū=二刀流=dual blade)
This is the hint to Musashi's realization of Nitenichiryū,
배가 불룩해져서 바로 잊어먹을 결정을 한 무사시.
but Musashi will probably forget soon as his tummy is full.
과연 숙명의 여신은 미소를 지어 줄까?
Will the goddess of fate smile at him?
カラのポケットに　ツキが
飛び込むことも　あるさ
おっきな声で　笑えば
あしたには　朝が来る
無くすものなんか　何もないさ
やっちゃえ！イケイケ！
手ぶらは　強いぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
人生　てなもんさ　チャンスが　ほら
しっぽを振って　追ってくるぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
未来も　てなもんさ　あしたが　ほら
両手ひろげて　笑ってるぜ
센히메 방위와 이도류 수행길에 떠난 우리 셋은 일단 동쪽으로 향했소.
The purpose of trip is protection of Senhime and exploration of dual blade technique;
we headed to the east first-dasu.
섬뜩한 늪에 다가갔을 때,
When we were at an eerie swamp,
말도 안 되게 거대한 두꺼비를 조종하는 이상한 카라쿠리 무예가가 나타났소.
a strange Karakuri Martial Artist controlling a giant toad has appeared-dasu.
그 자의 정체는 이하 사천왕의 하나, 지라이얀!
The name of that guy is Jiraiyan, one of Four Iga Kings!
다음 이야기! 거대 두꺼비 요술 지라이얀이오!
Next story! Giant Toad Magic, Jiraiyan!
질풍노도의 여행이오!
It'll be a stormy journey-dasu!
다음 이야기
거대 두꺼비 요술 지라이얀
기대하세요!
Next Episode
Giant Toad Magic
Jiraiyan
Look forwards for it!